Guide to the Frick Fine Arts Library Subject Files, 1939-1989 FFAL.001
ULS Frick Fine Arts Library
Frick Fine Arts Library Subject Files
1930-1989
1960-1979
ULS Frick Fine Arts Library
FFAL.001
20 Linear Feet
This collection consists of files on art subjects collected by library staff at the Frick Fine Arts Library. The majority of these items are from 1960-1979, though there are items from 1930-1989.
Arrangement
Files are listed alphabetically, roughly as they were found. The original structure of the files has been preserved.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection includes newspaper clippings, bibliographies, postcards, pamphlets, guidebooks, exhibition catalogs, and photographs. Notable items are indicated when appropriate.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
History
The Information Files of Frick Fine Arts Library were maintained from the library's inception in 1965 to approximately 1985. Some material dates prior to 1965, and the bulk of the material is from the 1960s and 1970s. A wide range of materials is contained within the files, including newspaper clippings, brochures, pamphlets, maps, mailings, posters, and other paper ephemera.
Related Material
Frick Fine Arts Library Artist Files, 1892-1990, FFAL.002, Frick Fine Arts Library, University of Pittsburgh
Art -- Library resources; Art -- 20th century
- Alchemy, 001 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 1)
- Allegheny County Courthouse Gallery / Forum, 1984-1985; 002; Two gallery exhibition postcards (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 2)
- Anatomy, 003 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 3)
- Animals in Art, 1940-1977; 004 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 4)
- Antiques, 1973; 005 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 5)
  Scope and Contents
  Notable item: Reproduction of Antique Fittings (catalogue), published by I. Sack, Boston, Mas., n.d., gift of Mary Roehrich, 1979
- Aqueous Open (Pittsburgh Watercolor Society Annual Exhibition), 1976-1987; 006 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 6)
- Archaeology, 007 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 7)
  Notable Items: Nineveh & Khorsabad: A note on the ruins for visitors, Printed at the Government Press, Baghdad, 1943.; The Archaeological Map of Iraq, n.d.; The Mustansiriya College: Its History and Architecture, Directorate General of Antiquities, Baghdad, 1960.
- Architectural Societies and Associations, 008 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 8)
  Contains one item: The Society of Architectural Historians 38th Annual Meeting Program, April 17-21, 1985.
- Architects A-J, 1937-1976; 009 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 9)
  Aalto, Alvar; Breuer, Marcel; Brace, William; Candella, Felix; Denby, Edwin; Doxiadis, Constantinos; Eames, Charles; Gaudi, Antonio; Gropius, Walter; Fuller, Buckminster; Hornbostel, Henry; Godefoy, Maximillan; Johnson, Philip; Kahn, Louis; Jefferson, Thomas; Johnson, Philip
- Architects L-Z, 1930-1980; 010 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 10)
  Jeanneret, Charles-Edouard (Le Corbusier); Mendelsohn, Eric; Mies Van Der Rohe, Ludwig; Neutra, Richard; Niemeyer, Oscar; Sullivan, Louis; Wright, Frank Lloyd
- Architecture -- Conservation and Preservation -- England, Germany, Italy, Etc., 011 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 11)
- Architecture Conservation & Restoration -- United States, 012 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 12)
  Notable Items: Letter to the Editor, by Lewis, Virginia E. (Associate Professor and Curator of Exhibitions, Frick FIne Arts Dept.), in Charette, January, 1955.
- Architecture -- General -- Modern, 19th Century; Modern, 20th Century, 013 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 13)
  Notable Items: Homes for Tomorrow, pub. Ladies' Home Journal.; Planning the Art Department: Plans and Specifications for a Modern Art Unit, by Winslow, Leon L., 1945.
- Architecture -- Belgium, 014 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 14)
  Notable Item: Bruxelles Grand'Place [postcard book], n.d., probably early 1900s, Editeur E. Desaix, Rue Moorslede, 10, Bruxelles.
- Architecture -- Burma, 015 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 15)
- Architecture -- Egypt, 016 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 16)
- Architecture -- England [Part 1], 017 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 17)
- Architecture -- England [Part 2], 018 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 18)
- Architecture -- England -- London, 019 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 19)
  Contents: Catalogue of the Designs offered for the New Houses of Parliament, Now Exhibiting in the National Gallery. Seventh Edition, June 25. London: Printed by W. Clowes and Sons, 14 Charing Cross, 1836, [disbound, partial copy]. "London of Tomorrow", Pittsburgh Press article, Sunday, November 22, 1942.
- Architecture -- France, 020 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 20)
- Architecture -- Germany; Architecture -- Holland; Architecture -- Hungary, 021 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 21)
- Architecture -- India; -- Ireland; -- Italy; -- Japan, 022 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 22)
- Architecture -- Russia, 023 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 23)
- Architecture -- Scotland, 024 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 24)
- Architecture -- Slavic; Architecture -- Turkish, 025 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 25)
- Architecture -- South America, 026 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 26)
- Architecture -- Sweden, 027 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 27)
- Architecture -- Syria, 028 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 28)
- Architecture -- U.S., 029 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 29)
- Arms and Armor, 030 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 30)
- Art -- Abstract, 031 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 31)
- Art -- African, 032 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 32)
- Art -- African-American, 033 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 33)
- Art -- American, 034 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 34)
- Art -- Ancient [Classical ], 035 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 35)
- Art -- Australian; Art -- Austria, 036 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 36)
- Art -- Baroque, 037 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 37)
- Art -- Bzyantine, 038 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 38)
- Art -- Chinese, 039 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 39)
  Notable Item: Ashimsa in Black and White, Volume II, by Feng, T. K., n.d., [University Library received 6-19-1941]
- Art -- Coptic, 040 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 40)
- Art -- Czechoslovakia, 041 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 41)
- Art -- Early Christian, 042 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 42)
- Art -- Egyptian, 043 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 43)
- Art -- Flemish, 044 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 44)
- Art -- French, 045 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 45)
- Art -- Germany, 046 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 46)
- Art -- Greenland, 047 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 47)
- Art -- India, 048 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 48)
- Art -- Indonesia, 049 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 49)
- Art -- Ireland, 050 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 50)
- Art -- Iran; -- Iraq; -- Israel, 051 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 51)
- Art -- Japanese; Art -- Korean, 052 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 52)
  Notable Items: A Sketch of the Historical Background of Japanese Art, by Fuller, Richard E., Seattle, Washington, 1935. [sample of, or advertisement for] Studie of the Temple Kokubunji, compiled by B. Tsunoda, 1938.
- Art -- Jewish; Art -- Liechtenstein, 053 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 53)
- Art -- Malaysia, 054 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 54)
- Art -- Mayan, 055 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 55)
- Art -- Medieval, 056 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 56)
- Art -- Mexican, 057 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 57)
  Notable Item: Veinte Dibujos Mexicanos: comentario de Jaime Torres Bodet. Biblioteca Accion: Madrid, 1928.
- Art -- Modern -- 20th Century, 058 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 58)
  Notable Items: Critique: A Review of Contemporary Art, Vol. 1, No. 1., ed. David Loshak, October 1946; "Art Viewers Mystified, Intrigued by Ritual", article on James Lee Byars performance art at Carnegie Museum of Art in Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, October 26, 1965.; Collages i maculatures, J. J. Tharrats, Barcelona, 1954.; The Coca Cola Flag by Mel Hanson [photograph], photo by Ray Andersen, [stamp] The Green Gallery, 3036 Fillmore Street, San Francisco, Calif. 94123.; [poster] Something Else Gallery, 238 West 22nd Street, New York City, (behind the Chelsea Hotel), Object Poems exhibit, April 16th to 27th, 1966.
- Art -- Oriental, 059 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 59)
- Art -- Pennsylvania German, 060 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 60)
- Art -- Persia, 061; Mainly composed of clippings from The Illustrated London News, 1930s-40s. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 61)
- Art -- Pre-Columbian, 062 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 62)
- Art -- Prehistoric, 063 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 63)
  Notable Item: [map] The Principal Cavern Regions of Southwestern Europe, including the caverns that contain Paleolithic Mural Decorations. Drawn by A. Briesemeister, based on the author's motor tour of 1912.
- Art -- Primitive, 064 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 64)
  Notable Item: Opportunity, A Journal of Negro Life, Vol. 4, No. 41, May 1926.; A. A. & A. Inc., (Archaeological Artifacts & Antiques, Inc.) catalog, 1963.
- Art -- Polish; -- Romanian, 065 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 65)
- Art -- Russia, 066 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 66)
- Art -- South Africa, 067 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 67)
- Art -- South America, 068 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 68)
- Art -- Spain, 069 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 69)
- Art -- Swiss; -- West Indian, 070 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 70)
- Art --Tibetan, 071 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Folder 71)
  Notable Items: Objects from the Tibetan Lamaist Collection of Jacques Marchais, 1941.
- Art -- Yugoslavia, 072 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 72)
- Art -- Addresses, essays, lectures -- General, and by author A-M, 073 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 73)
  Notable Item: Beck, Rosemarie. [opening lecture text] Paintings at the Peridot Gallery, Oct. 24 to Nov. 19, 1960.; Cuba, Ivan. [signed] The Evolution of Segmentation. 1965.
- Art -- Addresses, essays, lectures -- by author N-Z, 074 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 74)
  Notable Item: Shaw, Theodore L. Art at a Price: A New Approach to Aesthetics. 1941.
- Art -- Administration, 075; Contains one item: "Mastering the Art of Arts Administration" by Stephen Sinclair, The Cultural Post, pub. National Endowment for the Arts, Issue 16 March/April 1978. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 75)
- Art -- Appreciation, 076 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 76)
  Notable Item: Genies et Realites, pub. Hachette, Paris, n.d. [sample /advertisement ]
- Art -- Artists' Books, 077 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 77)
- Art -- Associations and Societies, 078 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 78)
- Art -- Associations and Societies -- Art Clubs, Commercial, 079 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 79)
- Art -- Associations and Societies -- Art Libraries Society of North America (ARLIS-NA), 080 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 80)
- Art -- Associations and Societies -- Associated Artists of Pittsburgh, 081 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 81)
- Art -- Associations and Societies -- College Art Association (CAA), 082 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 82)
- Art -- Associations and Societies -- Womens', 083 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 83)
- Art -- Centers, 084 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 84)
  Notable Item: Georges Pompidou brochure, 1975 (before opening in 1976)
- Art -- Collecting, 085 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 85)
- Art -- Competitions, 086 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 86)
  Notable Item: Literary Cavalcade, Part II, Teacher Edition, May, 1954. Vol. 6., No. 8. 1954 Scholastic Art Awards 27th National High School Art Exhibition, Fine Arts Galleries, Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, PA.
- Art -- Conferences, 087 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 87)
- Art -- Conservation and Restoration, 088 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 88)
  Notable Items: Hoffberg, Judith A. "To Preserve and to Protect: A Call to Action" [typescript ] Picturescope, Vol. 19, No. 2. [n.d.], library received Nov. 15, 1971. [signed] with fond memories, Judy. | War Department Pamphlet No. 31-103, Civil Affairs Information Guide, Field Protection of Objects of Art and Archives, War Department, 13 May 1944. | The UNESCO Courier, January 1967, Florence Venice, Unesco opens world campaign.
- Art -- Crafts and Arts, 089 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 89)
- Art -- Criticism, 090 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 90)
- Art -- Dealers, 091 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 91)
- Art -- Dictionaries, 092; Contains one item: Kaltenbach, G. E. Dictionary of Pronounciation of Artists' Names. Published by the Art Institute of Chicago, 1934. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 92)
- Art -- Economic Aspects, 093 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 93)
- Art -- Education, 094 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 94)
  Notable Item: Close Encounters of the Art Kind: Interactions in the Classroom and Museum. [worksheet packet] n.d., no creator.
- Art -- Foundations, 095; Contains one item: la Fondation Maeght, [brochure, rec. by library 11 March 1968.] (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 95)
- Art -- Funding, 096 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 96)
- Art -- History -- Ancient, 097; Contains one item: Hughes, Robert. "Gold of the Nomads". Time Magazine, April 21, 1975. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 97)
- Art -- History -- 20th Century, 098 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 98)
- Art -- Insane, by the, 099 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 99)
- Art -- Legislation, 100 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 100)
- Art -- Literature and Art, 101 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 101)
- Art -- Materials, 102 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 102)
  Notable Items: Typewritten letters pertaining to commercial standards for artists' oil paints, 1940-1942.
- Art -- Outlines, Syllabi, etc., 103; Contains one item: Fine Arts 1c, September 1926 [Harvard University (written in pencil), seems to be a syllabus/reading list] (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 103)
- Art -- Private Collections [Part 1], 104 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 104)
- Art -- Private Collections [Part 2], 105; by collector K-Z, numerous clippings about collectors in the Pittsburgh area (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 105)
  Notable Items: "Banker with a Fortune - in Art" Pittsburgh Post-Gazette article on Jay C. Leff, "the man behind current Carnegie exhibit", Dec. 27, 1969.
- Art -- Religion and Art, 106 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 106)
- Art -- Schools, 107 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 107)
- Art -- Science and Art, 108; Contains one item: "The heavens were brought down to earth by Copernicus the humanist", by J. Bronowski in Smithsonian magazine, April 1973. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 108)
- Art -- [the] State and Art, 109 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 109)
  Notable Items: Art as a Function of Government: A Survey, Issued by Supervisors Association of the WPA Federal Art Project, 1937.
- Art -- Study and Teaching [Part 1], 110 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 110)
  Notable Item: The Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art, Proceedings of the Installation of Edwin Sharp Burdell, the Sixth Director of the Cooper Union, November 3, 1938, pub. New York, 1939.
- Art -- Study and Teaching [Part 2], 111 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 111)
  Notable Items: Cultural Education under the Carnegie Grants for Art and Music, 1939-1945, printed 1944. Opportunities for Research in the City of Florence, by Professor Howard Saalman - possible duplicate with N6921 .F63511 [1965?]
- Art -- Technique, 112 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 112)
- Audio-Visual Materials, 113; Contains mostly slide library catalogues. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 113)
- Autographs, 114; Contains one item: XV. Urkunden und autographen des II. bis 19. Jahrhunderts (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 2, Folder 114)
- Bathing Machines, 115; Contains one item: "Bathing machines brought elegance to skinny dipping", by Peggy Heinrich and Ray J. Worssam, Smithsonian Magazine July 1974. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 115)
- Bibles, 116 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 116)
- Bibliography [Part I], 117 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 117)
  Chiefly bibliographies and lists of books acquired, from the library of the College of Ceramics at Alfred University. Notable Item: A Bibliography of Uncataloged Art Books and Historical Books in the Darlington Library, 1958, by Donald E. Roy. [typescript]
- Bibliography [Part II], 118 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 118)
- Bookbinding, 119 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 119)
  Notable Items: Bookbindings in the Public Collections of Denmark, Vol. I, The Royal Library Copenhagen, by Anker Kyster, Levin & Munksgaard, Ejnar Munksgaard, Copenhagen, 1938. [prospectus] 2 copies. English Bindings 1490-1940 in the Library of J. R. Abbey, ed. G. D. Hobson, The Chiswick Press, London, 1940. [prospectus]
- Bookplates, 120 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 120)
- Books, 121; Chiefly book club advertisements, some preservation information. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 121)
- Bronze, 122; Contains one item: Roman Bronze Works, Subsidary of General Bronze Corporation. [folder of advertising materials] (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 122)
- Calligraphy, 123 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 123)
  Notable Items: The Cherry Tree Legend, Shahn, Ben, Museum of Modern Art, New York, 1967. The University of Pittsburgh Book Center, Fine Books Room, Exhibition - Arnold Bank. [exhibition handout]. Our Handwriting, by Paul Standard, reprinted from Woman's Day, Dec. 1947. A Reproduction of the Lan-T'ing Calligraphy Scroll by Wang Hsi-Chih [guide to], by P'u Ju, March 5, 1961.
- Cards [playing], 124 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 124)
- Caricature and Cartoons, 125 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 125)
- Carlow College, Mellon Galleries, 126 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 126)
  Notable Items: Films by Pennsylvania Women [poster], June 1974.
- Carnegie Mellon University, 127 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 127)
- Carnegie Institute, Carnegie Museum, 128 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 128)
  Notable Items: Exhibition of Current American Prints, 1949, Department of Fine Arts, Carnegie Institute. Exhibition of German Expressionist Paintings from the Collection of Mr. and Mrs. Morton D. May, Carnegie Institute, Department of Fine Arts, 1962. The Graphic Arts in Pittsburgh, An exhibit presented during Pennsylvania Week by the Graphic Arts Committee of Pittsburgh, Carnegie Institute, October 1949.
- Chicago, 129; Contains one item: "Chicago" tourism pamphlet, circa 1940s. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 129)
- Children, Literature and Art, 130 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 130)
- China, 131 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 131)
- Christian Art and Symbolism, 132 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 132)
  Notable Items: Greeting card from Philip and Fanny Duschnes, December 1939, print from an original drawing by Valenti Angelo, one of 450 copies. Christ before Pilate, Christ on Cavalry, [on the paintings] by Michael de Munkacsy, by Rodman Wanamaker, 1926.
- Chromography, 133 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 133)
- Church Architecture, 134; Chiefly contains guidebooks and pamphlets to various churches and cathedrals. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 134)
- Cities and Towns - Planning, 135 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 135)
- The Clay Place, 136 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 136)
  Original Note on folder states: Descriptions/press releases for one-person shows are in artists' information file.
- Clocks and Watches, 137 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 137)
- Color, 138 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 138)
  Notable Items: Color, Drawing, Painting, E. Ambrose Webster, Provincetown, Mass. Printed by the "Eclaireur de Nice et du Sud-Est", n.d. Norathar, Talk on the Fine Art of Light-Color Play, delivered before the Women's Club of Washington, New Jersey, by Greenewalt, Mary Hallock, March 1942, [typescript].
- Communication, 139 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 139)
- Computer Art, 140 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 140)
  Notable Items: ASCII art of Mona Lisa and Alfred Newman (Mad Magazine), circa 1960s.
- Costume, 141 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 141)
- Craftsmens', Weavers', and Fiber Arts Guild of Pittsburgh, 142 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 142)
- Design, 143 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 143)
- Dolls, 144 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 144)
- Drawing, 145 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 145)
- Enamels, 146 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 146)
- Embroidery, 147 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 147)
- Eskimo Art, 148; Contains one item: "Eskimo Color Prints" article by Robert Moon, in the Christian Science Monitor, August 25, 1960. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 148)
- Esthetics [Aesthetics], 149 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 149)
- Exhibitions -- General, 150 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 150)
  Notable Items: A Century of Progess, 1833-1933, Chicago World's Fair Souvenir. Commemoration du centenaire de la Belgique, 1830-1930, Album Souvenir de l'exposition internationale d'anvers 1930. [picture album] Two Russian catelogs, both printed 1957.
- Facsimiles, 151 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 151)
  Contains six facsimilies of British and American pamphlets from 1600-1800, from Hammond Museum.
- Fallingwater, 152; Contains a brochure for Fallingwater circa 1970s. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 152)
- Festivals, 153 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 153)
  Notable Items: The Pittsburgh Forum, Vol. 5, No. 36, July-August 1975, Shadyside Summer Arts Festival Edition.
- Film Libraries, 154 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 154)
  Notable Items: A Cycle of 300 Films, brochure from the Museum of Modern Art Film Library, 1941. Shadow & Substance: The Art Film and Its Sources, Addison Gallery of American Art [exhibition pamphlet]. Study Guide to Alice Adams: Money Sequence and Dance Sequence, The Progressive Education Association, 1939. The Human Relations Series of Films, Commission on Human Relations, Progressive Education Association, 1939. Various bulletins from the Museum of Modern Art Film Library circa 1930-40.
- Fine China, 155 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 155)
- Finger Painting, 156; Contains one item: Finger Painting: An Outline of Its Origins and History by Francis R. Fast. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 156)
- Fire Engines, 157 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 157)
  Notable Item: Enjine! Enjine! A Story of Fire Protection by Kenneth Holcomb Dunshee, Published by Harold Vincent Smith for the Home Insurance Company, New York, 1939.
- Flags, 158; Contains one item: New Flags of 1960, article in Time Magazine, December 1960. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 158)
- Forgery of Works of Art, 159 (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 159)
- Frick, Helen Clay, 160; Chiefly newspaper articles. (File-cabinet 1, Drawer 3, Folder 160)